J. ALLSTON SCHWARTZ

Charleston, South Carolina 29407 | (843) 224-8492

iagschwartz@gmail.com | allstons.github.io/portfolio

PROFILE

Though I've worked in multiple disciplines, my focus lies in front-end development and interaction design. I have a passion for solving problems, constantly perfecting my craft, and producing work that I can be proud of. I'm currently seeing to expand my skills in a software development role, so if you're interested in hiring me, check out my work, and let's get in touch.

EDUCATION

The Iron Yard. / Frontend Developer

Georgia State University

January 2015 - March 2015

August 1995 - May 1998

Charleston, SC

12 week, intensive Frontend Development program

BA in English Literature and a minor in Theatre Arts (GPA 3.75) Atlanta, Ga

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING: HTML 5 CSS3/SASS JavaScript jQuery

Angular Backbone Underscore

TOOLS: Git/Github Command Line Version Control

Bower/NPM AJAX

DESIGN: Bootstrap

CMS: WordPress

EXPERIENCE

Addlestone Hebrew Academy

Teaching Assistant

Charleston, SC Feb 2013 – Jan 2015

- Created recorded text for students with language based learning disorders.
- Conducted small group and individual classroom activities with students based on differentiated learning needs to ensure all students were learning at their full potential.
- · Participated in ongoing staff training sessions.
- Organized parent-teacher conferences to maximize student learning opportunities and develop forward-thinking plans to correct ongoing issues.
- Employed assessment tools and proactive strategies to improve instruction methods.
- Assisted in producing curriculum that met state goals as well as the needs of the individual students.
- Worked with groups ranging from as little as 6 to as large as 30.

Inside the Envelope

CEO/Invitation Consultant

Charleston, SC Oct 2008 – Present

- Expertise in areas ranging from business administration to marketing invitations and creative services.
- Entrepreneur who through effective business planning, creative sales techniques, and innovative marketing, cultivated relationships with clients and vendors that garnered continued business and positive referrals.
- Recognized by clients and colleagues as a consummate professional with a high degree of personal integrity.
- Known for a contagious passion for excellence, ensuring consistent quality customer service to internal and external clients and attainment of individual and team goals.

FRONT END DEVELOPER